Louis Simpson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Louis Simpson Papers 1922-2011 (bulk 1937-2011)
MSS40154
Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012
66,000 items
212 containers plus 1 oversize
84.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Pulitzer Prize winning poet and author. Correspondence, working drafts of various poems and writings, administrative material regarding publishing and publications, reviews, translations, interviews, memorabilia, and subject files related to Simpson's career as an author and professor.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bellow, Saul--Correspondence.; Bly, Carol--Correspondence.; Bly, Robert--Correspondence.; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986--Correspondence.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989--Correspondence.; Cox, Brian, 1928-2008--Correspondence.; Fauchereau, Serge--Correspondence.; Flanagan, Thomas, 1923-2002--Correspondence.; Haines, John, 1924-2011--Correspondence.; Hall, Donald, 1928-2018--Correspondence.; Haydn, Hiram, 1907-1973--Correspondence.; Heaney, Seamus, 1939-2013--Correspondence.; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997--Correspondence.; Kenyon, Jane--Correspondence.; Kizer, Carolyn--Correspondence.; Kramer, Lotte--Correspondence.; Kray, Elizabeth D., 1916-1987--Correspondence.; Ledbetter, J. T.--Correspondence.; Lurie, Alison--Correspondence.; Marantz family--Correspondence.; Nolan, James, 1947- --Correspondence.; Nuccio, Mark--Art.; O'Siadhail, Micheal, 1947- --Correspondence.; Pack, Robert, 1929- --Correspondence.; Simpson family--Correspondence.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012. Adventures of the letter I. 1971.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012. At the end of the open road. 1963.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012. Caviare at the funeral. 1980.; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012. Searching for the ox. 1976.; Simpson, Rosalind De Marantz, 1905-1990--Correspondence.; Styron, William, 1925-2006--Correspondence.; Temko, Allan--Correspondence.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972--Correspondence.; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006--Correspondence.; Wheelock, John Hall, 1886-1978--Correspondence.; White, Claire Nicolas, 1925-2020--Correspondence.; White, Jon Manchip, 1924-2013--Correspondence.; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892--Portraits.; Wright, James, 1925-2000--Correspondence.
Organizations
Columbia University--Students.; State University of New York at Stony Brook--Faculty.; United States. Army.; University of California, Berkeley--Faculty.
Subjects
American poetry--20th century.; Literary prizes.; Literature.; Poetry--Periodicals.; Poetry.; Pulitzer Prizes.; World War, 1939-1945.
Titles
American poetry review.; Hudson review.; New Yorker.
Occupations
Authors.; Educators.
Provenance
The papers of Louis Simpson were first given to the Library of Congress in 1958 by Louis Simpson. Additional material was given in 1964, 1970, 1988, and 1998 by Louis Simpson and in 2018 by Matthew Simpson.
Transfers
Video and audio cassettes featuring interviews and poetry readings have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division where they are identified as part of the Louis Simpson Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Louis Simpson are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1923, Mar. 27 Born, Kingston, Jamaica
1933 1940 Attended Munro College, St. Elizabeth, Jamaica
1943 1946 U.S. Army, 101st Airborne Division
1948 B.S., Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1949 Published The Arrivistes. New York: Fine Editions Press Married Jeanne Rogers (divorced 1954)
1950 M.A., Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1950 1955 Associate editor, The Bobbs-Merrill Co.
1955 1959 Instructor, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1955 Married Dorothy Roochvarg (divorced 1979)
1957 Awarded the Prix de Rome
1959 Ph.D., Columbia University, New York, N.Y. Published A Dream of Governors. Connecticut: Wesleyan University Press
1959 1967 Professor of English, University of California, Berkeley. Berkeley, Calif.
1962 Published Riverside Drive. New York: Atheneum Books Recipient, Guggenheim Fellowship
1963 Published At the End of the the Open Road. Connecticut: Wesleyan University Press
1964 Awarded the Pulitzer Prize for poetry
1967 1993 Professor of English, State University of New York at Stony Brook, Stony Brook, N.Y.
1971 Published Adventures of the Letter I. New York: Harper and Row.
1972 Published North of Jamaica. New York: Harper and Row.
1976 Published Searching for the Ox. New York: William Morrow and Co.
1980 Published Caviare at the Funeral. New York: Franklin Watts, Inc.
1983 Published The Best Hour of the Night. New York: Ticknor and Fields
1985 Married Miriam Bachner (divorced 1998)
1990 Published In the Room We Share. New York: Paragon House
1994 Published The King My Father's Wreck. Oregon: Story Line Press
1997 Published Modern Poets of France: A Bilingual Anthology. Oregon: Story Line Press
2012, Sep. 18 Died, Stony Brook, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Louis Simpson (1923-2012) span the years 1922-2011, with the bulk of the material dated between 1937-2011. The papers contain correspondence, working drafts of various poems and prose, administrative material regarding publishing and publications, reviews, translations, interviews, memorabilia, copyright permissions, collected material, and subject files related to Simpson's career as an author and professor. The papers are organized into five series: Correspondence, Writings File, Professional File, Subject File, and Oversize.
The Correspondence series, arranged both alphabetically and chronologically, contains personal and professional correspondence with Louis Simpson’s many friends and associates in the literary world. Among the noted figures in the Correspondence series are: Saul Bellow, Brian Cox, Serge Fauchereau, Thomas Flanagan, John Haines, Hiram Haydn, Seamus Heaney, David Ignatow, Carolyn Kizer, Lotte Kramer, Elizabeth Kray, J. T. Ledbetter, Alison Lurie, James Nolan, Micheal O'Siadhail, Robert Pack, Allan Temko, Claire Nicolas White, Jon Manchip White, and James Wright. Featured within this series are correspondence with the poets Robert Bly, Donald Hall, Jane Kenyon, and writer Carol Bly, with whom Simpson wrote to frequently with throughout his life. The early correspondence between Simpson and his Columbia University mentor, Mark Van Doren are also included. Beyond the listed correspondents and personal correspondence, other material appearing in the Correspondence series features various aspects of Simpson’s professional life, potentially including material also found in the Professional File series such as speaking engagements, correspondence with publishers, and various administrative affairs.
Also included in the Correspondence series are letters between Louis and his family, notably his mother, Rosalind de Marantz, and his children, Anthony, Anne, and Matthew Simpson. Rosalind de Marantz lived in New York while Louis Simpson was a teenager at Munro College in Jamaica and later moved to Italy when Louis was an adult. While Louis served in the U.S. Army during World War II, he frequently wrote to his mother and the extended Marantz family.
The Writings File contains primarily working and edited drafts of various poems, prose, and other types of writings spanning Louis Simpson’s entire career. The papers document Simpson's evolution as a poet, moving from conventional poetic forms to a more Walt Whitman-influenced free verse style. Featured are Simpson’s drafts for books including Adventures of the Letter I, Caviare at the Funeral, Searching for the Ox, and At the End of the Open Road, for which he won the Pulitzer Prize for Poetry. Other featured works within the series include several unpublished notebooks, translations, and reviews of and by Simpson. Many of the papers included in the Writings File arrived at the Library in a state where it was extremely difficult to identify from which books, if any, many of the drafts originated. Effort was made to identify where possible what books belonged to which set of drafts; however, if a book could not be positively associated with a set of drafts, it was placed at the end of the series under the "working drafts" heading and arranged by circa date. Drafts of individually titled works can be found under the "poems, prose, and other writings" heading, but may also appear among the "working drafts." Documentation of Simpson's works published in anthologies, print magazines, newspapers, and poetry journals, are located under the features in "books and periodicals" heading. Poems and prose sent to Simpson from colleagues, fans, and friends, appear under the "other people's writings" heading.
The Professional File covers the administrative dealings of Simpson’s career in both the literary and academic world. Included in this series are various administrative memoranda regarding Simpson’s published works. Additionally featured is professional correspondence between periodicals that frequently published Simpson’s poems, including the American Poetry Review, American Scholar, New York Times, The New Yorker, Hudson Review, The Ohio Review, and The Gettysburg Review. Additional material related to publishing may be found within the general publishing correspondence folders.
Material concerning Simpson's academic career within the Professional File relates to both his time as a student at Columbia University and professorships he held at the University of California, Berkeley and State University of New York at Stony Brook. Also covered are Simpson’s Pulitzer Prize, his serving as a jury member for various literary awards, and his various engagements including poetry readings, speeches, and award ceremonies. Many of the poetry readings are documented on index cards with the date, location, and titles of poems read. Simpson's involvement in professional organizations such as the Academy of American Poets and the Guggenheim Foundation are documented as well.
The Subject File contains items collected from Louis Simpson’s personal filing cabinets, including memorabilia, scrapbooks, and printed material on various topics of interest. Major aspects of this series include Simpson’s awards, travel files, personal papers related to himself and his family, interviews, articles about Simpson, and personal recommendations for other poets, authors, and students.
The Oversize series contains two items: an undated poster for a poetry reading featuring a caricature of Louis Simpson and a woodcut-print portrait of Walt Whitman by Mark Nuccio, gifted to Louis Simpson in 1982 by members of the Walt Whitman Birthplace Association.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in five series:
Correspondence, 1939-2004
Writings File, 1937-2006
Professional File, 1940-2006
Subject File, 1922-2011
Oversize, 1982
Container List
- Correspondence, 1939-2004 (Box 1-46)
  Personal and professional correspondence with friends, associates, and family.
  Arranged alphabetically and chronologically therein.
  - Alphabetical (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Jack, 1971-1977, 1994-2001 (Box 1)
    - Bawer, Bruce, 1984-1995 (Box 1)
    - Bellow, Saul, circa 1955-1962, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Benedikt, Michael, 1963-1979, 1985, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Berg, Steve See Container 160, American Poetry Review (Box 1)
    - Berghash, Rachel, 1976-1997 (Box 1)
    - Bly, Carol, circa 1959-1964, 1996-2002, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Bly, Robert, circa 1958-2002, undated, (2 folders); (8 folders) (Box 1, Box 2)
    - Claeson, Stewe, 1988-2000 (Box 3)
    - Clark, Martha, 1977-1986 (Box 3)
    - Cox, Brian, 1964-2001 (Box 3)
    - D'Almeida, George, 1958-1964, 1971-1981, 1992 (Box 3)
    - de Marantz, Rosalind, circa 1939-1989, undated, (3 folders); (7 folders); (5 folders) (Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
    - DeMaria, Robert, 1980-1988 (Box 5)
    - Derricotte, Toi, 1983-1990, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Dodd, Wayne See Container 176, Ohio Review (Box 5)
    - Fauchereau, Serge, 1971-2001, undated See also Container 193, Fauchereau, Serge, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Flanagan, Thomas, circa 1960-1964, 1971-1980 (Box 6)
    - Galin, Saul, 1958-1972, 1980, 1989, undated (Box 6)
    - Haines, John, 1964-1967, 1978, 1991-1998 (Box 6)
    - Hall, Donald, circa 1954-2001, undated, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 6, Box 7, Box 8)
    - Harrison, Jim, 1967-1974, 1985, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Haydn, Hiram See Container 160, American Scholar; See Container 161, Athenum Publishers (Box 9)
    - Heaney, Seamus, 1971-1977, 1990-1994, undated (Box 9)
    - Heyer, William, 1974-1990 (Box 9)
    - Hitchcock, George, 1961-1966, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Hoffman, Theodore, 1949-1951, 1956-1957, 1963, 1969, 1975, undated (Box 9)
    - Hongo, Garrett Kaoru, 1986-1987, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Ignatow, David, 1956-1995, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Kenyon, Jane, 1975-1994 (Box 9)
    - Kizer, Carolyn, circa 1959-1971, 1987, 2000 (Box 10)
    - Kramer, Lotte, 1971-2000, undated, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Kray, Elizabeth See Container 160, Academy of American Poets (Box 10)
    - Lally, Margaret, 1950, 1973-1998, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 10, Box 11)
    - Lazer, Hank, 1980-1988 (Box 11)
    - Ledbetter, J. T., 1985-1997, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Levine, Robert, 1971-1994 See also Container 175, MacMillan Publishing Co.; See also Container 188, William Morrow and Co. (Box 11)
    - Lockwood, Willard See Container 188, Wesleyan University Press (Box 11)
    - Lurie, Alison, 1960-1969, 1979-1986 (Box 11)
    - MacShane, Frank, 1959-1978, undated (Box 11)
    - Marantz family, circa 1942-1989, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - MacDowell, Robert See Container 187, Story Line Press (Box 12)
    - Moran, Ronald, 1967-1991 (Box 12)
    - Morgan, Fred See Container 171, Hudson Review (Box 12)
    - Moss, Howard See Container 175, New Yorker (Box 12)
    - Nolan, James, 1970-1992, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - O'Siadhail, Micheal, 1990-1995 (Box 13)
    - Pack, Robert, 1956-1961 (Box 13)
    - Poulin, Jr., Abe See Container 161, BOA Editions Ltd. (Box 13)
    - Plumlee, Stanley See Container 176, Ohio Review (Box 13)
    - Reed, J. D., 1970-1974, 1995 (Box 13)
    - Resnick, Donald, 1991-2002, undated See also Container 203, Resnick, Donald, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Ribner, Irving, 1970-1972 (Box 13)
    - Roberson, William, 1978-1996 (Box 13)
    - Rompf, Kraft, 1971-1983, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Schneider, Steven, 2000-2002, undated (Box 14)
    - Sexton, Anne, 1959-1961, 1967 (Box 14)
    - Simpson, Anne, 1955-2000, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Box 15)
    - Simpson, Anthony, 1969-2000, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Simpson, Dorothy, 1957-1959, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Simpson, Jeanne, 1953-1975 (Box 16)
    - Simpson, Matthew, 1957-1994, 2000, undated, (5 folders) (Box 16)
    - Simpson family, 1949-1950, 1955, 1994, 2004 (Box 16)
    - Stitt, Peter, 1976-1994, 2004, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Temko, Allan, 1949-1950, 1956, undated (Box 17)
    - Thompson, Ralph, 1992-2003 See also Container 209, Thompson, Ralph (Box 17)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1941-1953, 1959-1964 See also Container 212, Van Doren, Mark (Box 17)
    - Waters, Michael, 1986-1997 (Box 17)
    - Webb, David and Mary, 1963-1979, undated (Box 17)
    - Weinberg, Helen, 1975-1977, undated (Box 18)
    - Wensberg, Erik, 1959-1976 (Box 18)
    - White, Claire, 1956, 1971-1976, 1983-2001, undated (Box 18)
    - White, Jon Manchip, 1992-2002 (Box 18)
    - Wright, James, 1960-1966, 1974-1979, 1990, 1999, undated (Box 18)
    - Yoon, Ho-Byeong, 1981-1995, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Chronological
    - 1948-1949 (Box 18)
    - 1950 (Box 18)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 19)
    - 1956, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - 1957 (Box 19)
    - 1958 (Box 19)
    - 1959 (Box 19)
    - circa 1950-1959 (Box 19)
    - 1960, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1961, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1962, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1963, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - 1964, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 21, Box 22)
    - 1965, (5 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1966, (5 folders) (Box 23)
    - 1967, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 23, Box 24)
    - 1968 (Box 24)
    - 1969 (Box 24)
    - circa 1960-1969, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1970, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1971, (4 folders) (Box 25)
    - 1972, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 25, Box 26)
    - 1973, (4 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1974, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 26, Box 27)
    - 1975, (3 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1976, (4 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1977, (2 folders) (Box 28, Box 29)
    - 1978, (4 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1979, (4 folders) (Box 30)
    - circa 1970-1979, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 30, Box 31)
    - 1980, (5 folders) (Box 31)
    - 1981, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - 1982, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 32, Box 33)
    - 1983, (2 folders) (Box 33, Box 34)
    - 1984, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 34, Box 35)
    - 1985, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 35, Box 36)
    - 1986, (3 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1987, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 36, Box 37)
    - 1988, (4 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1989, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 37, Box 38)
    - circa 1980-1989, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 38, Box 39)
    - 1990, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 39, Box 40)
    - 1991, (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1992, (4 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1993, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 41, Box 42)
    - 1994, (4 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1995, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1996, (2 folders) (Box 43, Box 44)
    - 1997, (3 folders) (Box 44)
    - 1998, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1999, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - circa 1990-1999, (3 folders) (Box 45)
    - 2000, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - 2001, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - 2002, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - circa 2000-2002 (Box 46)
    - undated (Box 46)
- Writings File, 1937-2006 (Box 47-159)
  Working and final drafts of poems, prose, essays, translations, reviews, and other types of published and unpublished writings.
  Arranged alphabetically by genre.
  - Books (Box 47)
    - Adventures of the Letter I
      - Working drafts, circa 1966-1971, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51)
      - Manuscript, 1971 (Box 51)
    - At the End of the Open Road, circa 1962, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 51, Box 52)
    - The Best Hour of the Night (Box 52)
      - Working drafts, circa 1980-1983, (4 folders); (6 folders) (Box 52, Box 53, Box 54)
      - Manuscript, 1983 (Box 54)
    - Caviare at the Funeral (Box 55)
      - Working drafts, circa 1980, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59)
      - Preface drafts, circa 1980 (Box 59)
      - Manuscript draft, circa 1980 (Box 59)
      - Galley proof, 1980 (Box 59)
      - Swedish translation, 1988 (Box 59)
    - Collected Poems (Box 60)
      - Preface drafts, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 60)
      - Manuscript, 1988, (5 folders) (Box 60)
    - A Dream of Governors, 1959, (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - In the Room We Share (Box 61)
      - Draft, 1989
      - Preface drafts, 1989 (Box 61)
      - Miscellany, 1989 (Box 61)
      - Manuscript, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - The King My Father's Wreck: A Memoir (Box 62)
      - Chapter drafts, circa 1991-1994, (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 63)
      - Manuscript draft, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 64)
      - Extra copies, circa 1993 (Box 64)
      - Discarded pieces, circa 1993 (Box 64)
      - Photographs, 1994 (Box 64)
    - The Legacy and The Testament by François Villon (Box 64)
      - Working drafts, circa 1998-2000, (2 folders) (Box 64, Box 65)
      - Revised drafts, circa 1998-2000, (4 folders) (Box 65)
      - Miscellany, circa 1996-2000 (Box 65)
    - Modern Poets of France: A Bilingual Anthology (Box 66)
      - Working drafts, circa 1992-1997, (7 folders); (5 folders) (Box 67, Box 68)
      - Preface drafts, circa 1992-1997, (2 folders) (Box 68)
      - Biographies, circa 1992-1997 (Box 69)
      - Manuscript draft, 1995, (4 folders) (Box 69)
      - Revisions, circa 1995-1997, (2 folders) (Box 69)
      - Copies of poems, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 70)
    - North of Jamaica (Box 70)
      - Working drafts, circa 1971, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 71)
      - Revised drafts, circa 1971, (2 folders) (Box 71)
      - Final draft, circa 1971, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 71, Box 72)
    - The Owner of the House, circa 1995-2000, (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 72, Box 73)
    - A Revolution in Taste (Box 73)
      - Drafts
        - Auden, W. H., circa 1977, (2 folders)
        - Auden, W. H. and Thomas, Dylan, circa 1977 (Box 74)
        - Footnotes, circa 1977 (Box 74)
        - Ginsberg, Allen, circa 1977 (Box 74)
        - Lowell, Robert, circa 1977 (Box 74)
        - Notes, circa 1977 (Box 74)
        - Olsen, Charles, circa 1977, (2 folders) (Box 74)
        - Plath, Sylvia, circa 1977 (Box 75)
        - Preface and afterword, circa 1977 (Box 75)
        - Thomas, Dylan, circa 1977, (2 folders) (Box 75)
      - Typescript, circa 1977, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 75, Box 76)
      - Manuscript, circa 1977, (3 folders) (Box 76)
      - Miscellany, circa 1977 (Box 76)
      - Discarded pages, circa 1977 (Box 76)
      - Uncorrected proof, 1978 (Box 76)
    - Riverside Drive (Box 77)
      - Working draft, circa 1961, (3 folders)
      - Discarded drafts, circa 1961, (2 folders) (Box 77)
      - Revised draft, circa 1961, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 77, Box 78)
      - Typescript, circa 1961, (6 folders) (Box 78)
    - Searching for the Ox (Box 79)
      - Working drafts, circa 1973-1976, (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 80, Box 81)
      - Preface drafts, circa 1973-1976, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 81, Box 82)
      - Manuscript, 1976 (Box 82)
      - Uncorrected proof, 1976 (Box 82)
      - Corrected proof, 1976 (Box 82)
    - There You Are (Box 82)
      - Working drafts, circa 1992-1995, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 83, Box 84)
      - Revisions, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 84)
      - Manuscript, 1995 (Box 84)
    - Three On The Tower: The Lives And Works of Ezra Pound, T. S. Eliot and William Carlos Williams (Box 85)
      - Draft
        - Eliot, T. S., circa 1974, (4 folders)
        - Pound, Ezra, circa 1974, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 85, Box 86)
        - Williams, William Carlos, circa 1974, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 86, Box 87)
        - Preface, circa 1974 (Box 87)
        - Afterword, circa 1974 (Box 87)
        - Footnotes, circa 1974, (2 folders) (Box 87)
        - Miscellany, circa 1974 (Box 87)
      - Work schedule, circa 1974 (Box 87)
      - Typescript, circa 1974, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 87, Box 88)
      - Manuscript, circa 1974, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 88, Box 89)
  - Collections (Box 89)
    - "Armidale", 1979
    - Copies of articles, circa 1970-2002, (2 folders) (Box 89, Box 90)
    - Copies of poems, circa 1949-2002, (4 folders); (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 90, Box 91, Box 92)
    - "Jamaica Poems", 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - "Occasions for Wonder" (Box 92)
      - First draft, 1992-1993 (Box 92)
      - Illustrations, 1992-1993 (Box 92)
      - Illustrations not used, 1992-1993 (Box 93)
    - "Out on the Island", circa 1993, (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - "People and Trees", 1992-1993, (5 folders) (Box 93)
    - Selected Prose (Box 94)
      - Table of contents, 1989 (Box 94)
      - "Entries", 1989, (3 folders) (Box 94)
      - "Some Letters", 1989, (2 folders) (Box 94)
    - "Wei Wei and Other Friends," 1990 (Box 94)
    - Yale Series of Recorded Poets, 1961 (Box 94)
  - Features in Other Books and Periodicals (Box 95)
    - 1941-1976, (5 folders)
    - 1977-1989, (5 folders) (Box 96)
    - 1990-2002, (5 folders) (Box 97)
  - Miscellany (Box 98)
    - "Anthology of American Writing," circa 1950 (Box 98)
    - Autobiography, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 98)